- Imagine you're stuck in a long meeting,
-想像一下你被困在一個長時間的會議中，
and your coworker is taking everyone's lunch order.
而你的同事正在接收大家的午餐點。
You say you'd like a sandwich,
你說你想要一個三明治
and they end up ordering you a tuna fish sandwich,
，他們最終會給你點一個金槍魚三明治
which is not your thing.
，這不是你的喜歡
Since you didn't clearly communicate
由於您沒有清楚地傳達自
exactly what you wanted, you didn't get a great outcome
己想要的內容，因此儘管您的同事願意幫助，
despite your coworker's willingness to help.
但仍然沒有獲得出色的結果。
AI works similarly.
AI 的工作方式類似。
It's best when you communicate clearly to get what you want.
當您清楚地溝通以獲得所需的最佳選擇。
You need to make sure you're giving it detailed instructions
您需要確保您給它詳細的說明
and asking good questions.
並提出好的問題。
This is called prompting.
這稱為提示。
When you prompt AI, there are many ways to go about it,
當您提示 AI 時，有很多方法可以進行，
but the key principles are being clear
但關鍵原則是清晰
and providing context.
並提供背景。
We'll start with a framework you can use
我們將從一個可以使用的框架開始
to make sure your prompts have clear directions
，以確保提示具有明確的指示
and relevant information.
和相關信息。
This gives you a solid structure
這為您提供了對
and guidelines for what to say to AI so you aren't guessing.
AI 說什麼的堅實結構和指導方針，因此您不會猜測。
I'll show you how this works in Gemini.
我將向您展示這在雙子座中的工作原理。
Consider this scenario.
考慮這個案例。
You're looking for advice
您正在尋找有
on how to make a meeting more effective.
關如何使會議更有效的建議。
We'll start by going to gemini.google.com.
我們會先前往雙胞胎網站。
First, describe the persona that you want Gemini to take on.
首先，描述您希望雙子座扮演的角色。
That means decide what expertise or knowledge
這意味著在解釋您想要的內容之前
you want Gemini to draw from
，先決定您希望雙子座從哪
before explaining what you want.
些專業知識或知識中獲得。
In this example, you could tell Gemini
在這個例子中，您可
to take on the persona of someone who's highly experienced
以告訴 Gemini 接受大型項目經驗豐富的人
with large projects, which tend to require lots of meetings.
的角色，這些項目往往需要大量會議。
"You are a seasoned team leader
「您是一位經驗豐富的團隊負責
with a proven track record of managing large projects."
人，在管理大型項目方面擁有證實的記錄。」
Then describe a task you want AI to help you with.
然後描述您希望 AI 協助您完成的任務。
"Give me some tips for running more effective meetings."
「給我一些提示，以進行更有效的會議。」
Next, specify the format
接下來，通過告
by telling Gemini what the output should look like.
訴 Gemini 輸出應該是什麼樣的來指定格式。
It could be a list of pros and cons, bullet points,
它可能是優缺點列表，項目符號，
or a specific length or tone.
或特定長度或色調。
Let's add, "Format your response as a bullet list."
讓我們添加，「將您的回應格式化為項目符號列表。」
Now you need to set the context.
現在您需要設置上下文。
Ask yourself, what does AI need to know
問問自己，AI 需要知道什麼
in order to get this right?
才能正確地做到這一點？
For starters, AI doesn't know how large your company is
對於初學者來說，AI 不知道您的公司有多大
or how teams work together.
或團隊如何共同合作。
It also doesn't know your unique challenge,
它也不知道您的獨特挑戰，即在
which is making clear decisions during status meetings.
狀態會議期間做出明確的決定。我
We'll add, "Our teams often work cross-functionally,
們會補充說，「我們的團隊通常會跨職能工作
and we're struggling to make clear decisions
，而且我們在
on some aspects of the project during our status meetings."
狀態會議期間對項目的某些方面做出明確的決定。」
One more note on the framework.
關於框架的另一個注意事項。
There are plenty of ways to construct an effective prompt.
有很多方法可以構建有效的提示。
The order in which you construct a prompt is less important
建構提示的順序與提示本身
than the substance of the prompt itself.
的內容不太重要。
Now let's run our prompt and see what we get.
現在讓我們運行我們的提示，看看我們得到什麼。
Hmm.
嗯。
Okay, the idea of assigning a dedicated decision maker
好吧，指派專門的決策者和筆記
and a note taker is interesting.
者的想法很有趣。
It does help to know who has which role
在
before the meeting starts.
會議開始之前，知道誰擔任哪個角色確實有幫助。
before you use it.
使用之前，請務必檢查 AI 給您的輸出。
This is a crucial step.
這是一個重要的步驟。
In some cases, the first response you receive
在某些情況下，您收到的第一個回應
may have room for improvement.
可能會有改進的空間。
Maybe the different folks on my team
也許我團隊中的不同人
work in different time zones,
在不同的時區工作，
and it's hard to get the dedicated decision maker
而且很難找到專門的決策者參加
in the meeting because it's outside of their working hours.
會議，因為這是在他們的工作時間以外。
You can add this context right into the same chat
您可以將這個上下文直接添加到同一聊
and ask it to update its advice
天中，並要求它
based on the additional information.
根據其他信息更新其建議。
Prompting is a foundational skill
提示是使用 AI 獲得卓越成
for getting great results with AI.
果的基礎技能。
Here are a few more tips that can help elevate your prompts.
以下是一些可以幫助提高提示的其他提示的提示。
Provide an example or a reference.
提供範例或參考。
Just like seeing an example helps you understand a task,
就像看一個例子可以幫助您了解任務一樣，
giving one to AI helps it understand your needs.
將其交給 AI 可以幫助它了解您的需求。
If you're looking for advice on running a meeting,
如果您正在尋找有關舉行會議的建議，請
attach a past agenda as a reference.
附上過去的議程作為參考。提示
It's also helpful to enlist
時，利用
Gemini's multimodal capabilities when prompting
Gemini 的多模式功能也很有幫助，以幫助它更
to help it better understand what you're looking for.
好地了解您正在尋找的內容。
This means including different types of media
這意味著在
in your prompt, like documents, images, or websites.
提示中包含不同類型的媒體，例如文檔、圖像或網站。
Think about how you would communicate with a hairdresser.
想想您將如何與美髮師交流。
You might describe what haircut you want using words,
您可能會用單詞描述想要的髮型，
but sometimes showing a picture can be more helpful.
但有時顯示圖片可能會更有幫助。
You can do the same with Gemini.
您可以對雙子座做同樣的事情。
You may need to use several prompts
您可能需要使用幾個提示
to keep on improving your output.
來繼續改善輸出。
This process is called iteration,
這個過程稱為迭代
and there's a few ways to do it.
，有幾種方法可以做到這一點。
First, you can edit your initial prompt.
首先，您可以編輯初始提示。
For example, you can add more details
例如，您可以為角色、任務、
to the persona, task, format, or context,
格式或前後關聯新增更多詳細資訊，也可以
or you can try writing a similar prompt
嘗試使用不同的
with different phrasing.
短語編寫類似的提示。
Another option, you can break up your prompt
另一個選項，您可以將提示分
into smaller parts.
成更小的部分。
Instead of asking for a full solution all in one go,
而不是一次要求完整的解決方案，
you could first ask for principles
您可以首先要求有
of effective decision making.
效決策的原則。
Then you could follow up
然後，您可以跟
and ask how you could apply those principles
進並詢問如何在會議
in your meetings.
中應用這些原則。
Finally, you could ask for a meeting agenda
最後，您可以要求一個會議議程
that will better enable decision making.
，以便更好地進行決策。
This process helps AI
此程序可幫
to reason through each part of the request at a time.
助 AI 一次理解請求的每個部分。
You're focusing it on a smaller task
您將它專注於較小的任務，
and checking in along the way.
並在此過程中進行報到。
Finally, you can add constraints into your prompt.
最後，您可以將約束添加到提示中。
Constraints are requirements that the AI should meet.
限制是 AI 應符合的要求。
For example, "Provide solutions
例如，「提供
that can be implemented within a week,"
可在一週內實作的解決方案」
or, "Don't suggest lengthening the meeting."
或「不建議延長會議」。
Okay, one last tip.
好吧，最後一個小提示
Remember to use one chat per topic.
記得每個主題使用一個聊天。
That's because everything you enter into a single chat
這是因為您在單一聊天中輸入的所有內容都
becomes context for AI.
會成為 AI 的上下文。
This is possible because of long context windows,
這是可能的是因為上下文窗口長，
meaning you can keep the chat going
這意味著您可以繼續進行
and even return to it days or weeks later
聊天，甚至幾天或幾週後返回聊
and pick up right where you left off.
天，並在停止的地方繼續進行。
But if you switch to a new topic in that same chat,
但是，如果您在同一聊天中切換到新主題，
things might get confused,
情況可能會變得混亂，
so when changing topics, always start a new chat.
因此在更改主題時，始終開始新的聊天。
Putting this framework and tips into practice
將這個框架和技巧實踐為
is the key to effective prompting.
實踐是有效提示的關鍵。
This approach will help you better guide AI
這種方法將幫助您更好地指
towards the results that you're looking for.
導 AI 實現您正在尋找的結果。
And the more you practice, experiment,
您越多練習，實驗
and get more comfortable,
並感到更舒適，
the better your results will become.
您的結果就越好。
Most importantly, as you continue writing prompts
最重要
that add more value to your work.
的是，當您繼續為不同類型的任務撰寫提示時，您使用 AI 的方式將從簡單的命令發展到持續進行協作對話，為您的工作增加更多價值。
For example, once I planned a trip,
例如，一旦我計劃一次旅行，
and I found that it was really useful
我發現在添
to add the ages of the people who were traveling
加旅行的人的年齡，
and then to return in the future
然後在日
when the dates changed to find out,
期改變時返回來
did the itinerary that I had before work,
了解，我在工作前的行程是否真的很有用，
or did it need to be updated?
還是需要更新？
Ready to keep building from here? Let's go.
準備好從這裡繼續建造嗎？我們走吧